Abdelhak RAHMOUNI

Software engineer

+213 780 48 96 07 | rahmouni.abdelhak.1@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/rahmouni-abdelhak | github.com/abdel7ak96 | abdel7ak96.github.io

SUMMARY

I'm a software engineer and a computer science master's degree graduate with an insatiable curiosity. I have professional experience building software for multiple platforms and with multiple teams. I am autonomous and a self-learner that loves to constantly evolve.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer

Mar 2022 - Feb 2023

Shard Labs - Full-time

Zagreb, Croatia (Remote)

- Actively maintained and developed new features to the front-end of our crypto staking solution on Polygon blockchain.
- Built and integrated the front-end of a crypto lending and borrowing protocol on Aurora blockchain.
- Built and integrated the front-end of a Proof-Of-Attendance-Protocol application on NEAR blockchain.
- Reviewed code and ensured our code bases stayed consistent and adhered to clean-code best practices.

Full Stack Web Developer

Nov 2021 - Mar 2022

Namla Cloud - Full-time

Paris, France (Remote)

- Spearheaded the development of a cloud orchestration & management platform using React & TypeScript.
- Effectively documented each newly created component on Confluence.
- Voluntarily took on tasks related to DevOps to meet deadlines and improve my skillset.
- Implemented the company's first website.

Full Stack Developer

Aug 2021 - Sept 2021

Barsha Technology - Freelance

Gabes, Tunisia (Remote)

- Created a compliance checking tool for a client based offshore as a mobile app using Flutter.
- Implemented introduction slideshow to showcase the procedure
- Slide animation for seamless progression through compliance checking steps.
- Implemented Google Sheets API as the backend to save data.

EDUCATION

University of Science and Technology of Oran - MB

Oran, Algeria

Master degree in Information & Data Systems

Sept. 2019 - Sept. 2021

University of Science and Technology of Oran - MB

Oran, Algeria

Licence degree in Computer Science

Sept. 2016 – Juin 2019

PROJECTS

Verum: Decentralized voting platform | React, Ethereum, JavaScript, Solidity, Bootstrap

July 2021

- Developed an admin dashboard allowing the user to launch and control ongoing voting events.
- · Developed a voter application that allows a user to authenticate and cast a vote
- · Implemented a voting smart contract and deployed it to a personal blockchain

Inception Extension | Chrome API, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Sept 2020

- Developed a browser extension that allows a user to travel to the very first commit of any Github repository
- Used DOM manipulation to place a button on the page seamlessly
- Fetched Github API for the proper commit hash for constructing the first commit's url

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: TypeScript, Java, Python, C/C++, SQL, PL/SQL, HTML/CSS, Dart, PHP

Frameworks: React, Express, Vue, Flutter, GraphQL **Developer Tools**: Git, VSCode, Eclipse, TravisCI, Docker

Libraries: Tailwind, Bootstrap, Ethers.js

Design: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Figma

Others: Jira, ClickUp, Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Wordpress, LaTeX

CERTIFICATIONS

- Responsive Web Design Certification FreeCodeCamp
- JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures Certification FreeCodeCamp
- Front End Libraries Certification FreeCodeCamp
- Ultra fast applications using Node.js Openclassroom
- Go Full-Stack With Node.js, Express, and MongoDB Openclassroom
- Manage Your Code Project With Git & Github Openclassroom